A Guide to the Julia Finette Davis Research Files, ca. 1960s
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Julia Finette Davis Research Files ca. 1960s
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 1996.45 20C
.5 linear feet.
Davis, Julia Finette
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Unknown
Biographical/Historical Information
Julia Finette Davis was a consultant to the Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Scope and Content
Davis' papers focus on the history of fruit growing in the United States. Much of the information has been photocopied.
Arrangement
Arranged in alphabetical order.
Index Terms
Persons:
Davis, Julia Finette
Subjects:
Fruit - History
Contents List
- Garden Research Files
  - Authors (Box 1)
    - Beach, Spencer A., The Apples of New York
    - Coxe, William
      - Copy from manuscript treatise and view of Fruit Trees in America
      - Index to A View of Cultivation of Fruit Trees
      - Notes from A View of the Cultivation of Fruit Trees
    - Faureth, "Colonial Gardens and Plants"
    - Favretti, Rudy J., "New England Colonial Gardens"
    - Fletcher, S.W., "A History of Fruit Growing in America"
    - Hornsby, Planting diary
    - Humphreys, "Spectacle de la Nature"
    - Prince, William Robert, "Treatise on the Vine"
    - Quincy, Josiah, Journal, 1773
    - Reuter, C.G., Flore and Fauna in Wachovia, 1760 1758
    - Ritson, Anne, "Political Picture of America"
    - Worlidge, "Vinetum Britannicum"
  - Carter's Grove
    - Proposals
    - Purpose, Scope, and Outline of Proposed Research
  - Cider
    - Directions for making
    - English material
    - Extract concerning, 1721
    - Material from Bulmers
    - Mills (from Eric Sloane's book)
    - Recipes (for wine, also)
  - Fruit
    - 19th century information, Anderson, Robert information
    - Apples
      - Descriptions of old varieties
      - Hughes seedlings
      - Newtown (Abermarle) Pippin, ca. 1889
      - Varieties
      - Varieties, Kirby, S.F. Account Book, 1785-1804
    - Catalogues
      - Baum's Nursery, 1960-1970
      - Furber, 1732
      - Prince, William
      - Southmeadow and Converse, 1968
    - Crab apple
      - Orchard, account of
      - Virginia, account, 1814
      - Williamsburg or Chiswell
    - Grapes
      - Forced/Vineyard, "Observations on Culture of Vines", Universal Magazine
      - Varieties
    - Information, species and families
    - Kitchen gardens
    - List, Anderson, Robert, 1835
    - Notes
      - Ambassador Collection
      - English books
      - Jefferson, Thomas, "The Garden Book"
      - Jefferson, Thomas, Papers
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
      - Skipwith, Joan, Prestwould, ca. 1780
      - Tucker, St. George, 1786-1790
      - Washington, George, Papers
    - Nursery ads, "Richmond Inquirer", 1823
    - Oregon Historical Society Pioneer Orchard
    - Peach, Double Blossom, Universal Magazine, 1754
    - Pears, Shapes of Old Sturbridge Village Collection
    - Varieties
      - Desired by Hagley Museum
      - Modern, Nelson County Orchards, VA
  - Plants
    - Identification of material from Custis well
    - List from Garden Symposium
    - List of plants in Colonial Williamsburg
  - Publication materials
    - Bibliography, Landscape and Garden Report, (2 folders)
    - Plates
  - Miscellaneous
    - Chronicle data on tools to pare, pit fruits
    - Plantation layout, Mount Vernon
    - Virginia Gazette, references to outhouses